<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>t3rse</title>
    <link>http://www.t3rse.com/categories/technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on t3rse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.t3rse.com/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Desktop</title>
      <link>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2015-06-29-post-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 13:52:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2015-06-29-post-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about a blog is that you can trace decisions you blogged about to the exact date. It was July 18, 2013 when I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.t3rse.com/2013/07/18/Moving-Forward-Backward/&#34;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; using a desktop pc rather than a laptop. It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting journey but it came crashing (pun intended) to a halt when my desktop died a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s lazy writing but I&amp;rsquo;ll bullet point a few random thoughts about 2+ years on a desktop:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home built desktops are more powerful for the price. I was able to run a bunch of VMs, IDEs, games without thinking about resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running powerful hardware is often noisy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desktops make you sedentary. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t just that I stopped leaving the house, I stopped leaving my desk. Whereas before I&amp;rsquo;d occasionally work in a coffee shop. I even forgot how handy it is to work in different parts of the house (e.g. kitchen table).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desktops are noisy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although mobile devices let you do a lot of &amp;lsquo;reading&amp;rsquo; away from your desk, they aren&amp;rsquo;t very good for writing: email, blog posts, code - you name it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home built desktops make you into a hardware technician whether you like it or (in my case) not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experiences, especially in having to troubleshoot hardware, have led me to the conclusion that while the desktop experiment had some upside, I prefer an indestructible laptop if only because the hardware configuration is more stable. Yes, it is possible to have a flakey laptop but I&amp;rsquo;m several generations into Lenovo and they&amp;rsquo;ve all been solid. The big question going forward is whether my next laptop is a Lenovo or a Macbook. I suspect the latter but time (and the pocket book) will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>