<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>t3rse</title>
    <link>http://www.t3rse.com/categories/tech/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on t3rse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.t3rse.com/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Listening Habits</title>
      <link>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2015-10-26-podcast-listening-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 17:36:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2015-10-26-podcast-listening-habits/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My colleague Staxmanade is building a &lt;a href=&#34;http://staxmanade.com/apps/xbox-one-podcast/development/&#34;&gt;podcast app for XBox&lt;/a&gt;. You should check it out, he&amp;rsquo;s good at what he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our conversations I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to catalog my habits around listening to podcasts. Not to navel gaze for its own sake, more because I&amp;rsquo;m curious about what YOUR habits are and what the more broader trends are beyond my sample size of 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;i-use-pocket-casts-http-www-shiftyjelly-com-pocketcasts-for-just-about-everything-because-it-s-on-my-phone-and-i-take-my-phone-everywhere-even-jogging&#34;&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shiftyjelly.com/pocketcasts&#34;&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt; for just about everything because it&amp;rsquo;s on my phone and I take my phone everywhere (even jogging).&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will occasionally listen in-browser when I either want to test-drive a podcast or listen to a single episode. This happens maybe once or twice a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;i-m-a-stop-and-go-listener&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a stop-and-go listener.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very rare to listen to a podcast from start to finish without pausing. For example, my son comes to visit my office. I get a refill of coffee. I&amp;rsquo;m walking to the car. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;quality-does-not-matter-but-sometimes-it-does&#34;&gt;Quality does NOT matter but sometimes it does.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When any podcaster I listen to starts down the trail of what mic they use and other details, my eyes glaze over. Content is what drives me to a podcast - if &lt;a href=&#34;http://hanselminutes.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; is interviewing someone interesting over a skype call and they have an Israeli accent, I will crane my neck and listen because the content is good. With that said, there are shows like &lt;a href=&#34;http://thisdeveloperslife.com/&#34;&gt;This Developers Life&lt;/a&gt; which were compelling because of the care and detail put into eachepisode. This was not because they purchased any of the mics podcasters like talking about, it was because of Rob&amp;rsquo;s post production and editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;podcasts-i-listen-to-involve-multiple-people&#34;&gt;Podcasts I listen to involve multiple people.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is incredibly hard for a single person to be engaging over any length of time. Conversations work best. A great
hybrid is a personal essay that opens each show - Debbie Millman used to do this on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debbiemillman.com/designmatters/&#34;&gt;Design Matters&lt;/a&gt;. More recently Tim Ferris has used this tactic as well. But for
show content, conversations work best. There is one notable exception to this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dancarlin.com/hardcore-history-series/&#34;&gt;Hardcore History&lt;/a&gt; although despite his claims that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much planning Dan Carlin seems to present his content in an effecient, essay-like narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;often-i-don-t-finish-especially-long-podcasts-going-more-than-40-minutes&#34;&gt;Often I don&amp;rsquo;t finish. Especially long podcasts going more than 40 minutes.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work from home so perhaps with a commute this woul be different. But even then,
some of the podcasts that stretch into the 2+ hour range almost seem like work in order to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;i-switch-a-lot-even-mid-podcast&#34;&gt;I switch a lot. Even mid-podcast.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give an idea of how this works, I might be listening to a long podcast like ATP in the morning but when I take a walk
(usually 20 minutes) I like to have something I can start and finish so I&amp;rsquo;ll switch to something shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;despite-all-the-podcasts-i-subscribe-to-there-are-few-that-i-m-religious-about-listening-to&#34;&gt;Despite all the podcasts I subscribe to there are few that I&amp;rsquo;m religious about listening to.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll drift for a while and then binge through a few episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few thoughts on podcasts but enough of my own narcisicm. I&amp;rsquo;m curious about any other habits, tactics, or nuances people might have when it comes to listening to podcasts. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already
been there, please check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://staxmanade.com/apps/xbox-one-podcast/development/&#34;&gt;Staxmanade&amp;rsquo;s podcast app&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m lobbying for a version that will run in a browser for those of us without Xboxes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter Questions</title>
      <link>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2015-07-17-newsletter-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 14:29:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2015-07-17-newsletter-questions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s very hard to go through a web browsing session without having a modal dialog popup to ask for your email address. Or how about this: you go to a website and in the margins there is an offer: enter your email address to receive &lt;strong&gt;The Completely Free Guide to X&lt;/strong&gt; or some other PDF document, usually written by the author of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The playbook, from bloggers&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; to marketing agencies to big companies is simple: harvest email addresses, constantly engage through email marketing newsletters&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases this is done in earnest; the person asking for your email address is crafting a message as an act of community building&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;. Other cases are less sinister than they are purely commercial; your email address is a monetization unit. They will try to make money by bundling you up with others and in turn, you’ll give them a chance because the carrot at the end of the stick (daily deal?) is worth an email address (maybe not your primary – maybe a specific one you’ve designed for just this purpose).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I occasionally write &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.t3rse.com/articles/&#34;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.argusleader.com/news/business-journal/&#34;&gt;Sioux Falls Business Journal&lt;/a&gt; and I want to explore the impact of newsletters as well as different ways to manage all of the email they generate. As an informal survey I’m looking for answers/opinions on the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you subscribe to any newsletters or email marketing offers (think daily deals like Groupon)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many emails would you guess you get (daily or weekly, please specify) that are newsletters or solicitations?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you use any specific tactics to manage non-personal/non-work email that they generate?
Here are some common techniques (though do tell if you do something different):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A burner email address that is not your primary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Priority Inbox at gmail / Outlook.com features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your own customized filtering scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gmail aliases (e.g. david.smith+newsletter@gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third party service: IFTT or Unroll.me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote (send newsletters to a notebook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;I used to consider myself a &amp;ldquo;blogger&amp;rdquo; though these days I&amp;rsquo;ve had to reconsider since the wordpress + plugins universe is so different in form and substance from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00994UMH4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00994UMH4&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=t3rse-20&amp;amp;linkId=I4F3XXAGKLKBRPMJ&#34;&gt;Rebecca Blood&lt;/a&gt; version I knew before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that most of my &amp;ldquo;old school&amp;rdquo; blogs don&amp;rsquo;t work this way, even the popular ones (e.g. xkcd). They seem built for a time when most readers kept up via RSS readers rather than the inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;######&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;It might not be clear but I really do &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; these. A part of my exploration of the newsletter world is to think about ways I can optimize  my consumption of curated thoughts like those from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brainpickings.org/&#34;&gt;Brainpickings&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/&#34;&gt;Farnam Street&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve got mixed feelings about the strictly commercial ones, especially the ones which have no other intended purpose than to make money for the owner and whomever else they share email addresses with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trend Talk</title>
      <link>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2014-06-04-trend-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 23:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.t3rse.com/post/2014-06-04-trend-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first developer conference I ever attended was VBITS (&amp;ldquo;Visual Basic Insider&amp;rsquo;s Technical Summit&amp;rdquo; - now defunct) in San Francisco. I won&amp;rsquo;t forget that experience or the keynote from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/psaffo&#34;&gt;Paul Saffo&lt;/a&gt;, a futurist who exhorted us to look beyond our technological present and to try to anticipate and respond to trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not completely my own efforts but something must have stuck: learning about vtable binding and COM was useful but I also realized that I needed to do everything I could to get involved with web development. Soon after I was doing a lot more with Visual Interdev than I was with Visual Basic - and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kpcb.com/partner/mary-meeker&#34;&gt;Mary Meeker&lt;/a&gt; recently released her 2014 Internet Trends Report and it&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity, these many years down the road, to try to see the big picture and get a bigger sense of direction. I looked at a few versions: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kpcb.com/internet-trends&#34;&gt;the primary source&lt;/a&gt; and a helpful &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/gallery/mary-meeker-internet-trends/&#34;&gt;annotated version&lt;/a&gt; on TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my takeaways: (apologies for going &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/nthings.html&#34;&gt;List of N&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile is the place to be as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate to be a full time Android dev at present and it will be important to hone and improve the skill set. Apple&amp;rsquo;s recent announcement of Swift is an opportunity to get in on the ground floor of iOS development as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personal Education&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of declining quality of education, online education is at a groundswell for those who are willing to take initiative. Taking initiative is easy for me (I love learning) but I&amp;rsquo;m easily distracted so focusing on a single topic or subject matter area is more of a challenge. Coursera has recently launched educational tracks (Android, Data Science) which will help with this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Single Purpose Apps / Invisible Apps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps should be designed to do one thing. Invisible apps leverage notification, context, and predictive computation to give you information when you need it. Here is the quote lifted from slide 41:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We’re entering the age of apps as service layers.
  These are apps you have on your phone but only open
  when you know they explicitly have something to say to you.
  They aren’t for ‘idle browsing,’ they’re purpose-built &amp;amp;
  informed by contextual signals like hardware sensors,
  location, history of use &amp;amp; predictive computation.&amp;rdquo;
  – Matthew Panzarino, TechCrunch, 5/15/14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mindset to date is on apps that users interact with but I need to start thinking more of apps as a way of passively doing things for the user - as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deepelement.com/articles&#34;&gt;my colleague&lt;/a&gt; at Vertigo put it: &amp;ldquo;giving [users] an additional sense.&amp;rdquo; Sometimes this can be a simple matter of phrasing; several times now &lt;a href=&#34;http://forecast.io&#34;&gt;forecast.io&lt;/a&gt; will tell me it will be raining &amp;ldquo;in a few minutes&amp;rdquo; with incredible accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design as a feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rethinking old concepts (e.g. Yellow pages) in mobile design. I was impressed by the WWDC 2014 keynote in which Apple demonstrated for those of us who have forgotten that for them, design is a feature. I saw people joking during the keynote about all the references to transparency in UI of the new version of OSX, Yosemite, but in my mind spending as much time in the keynote on the topic just shows how important it is on their part for things to look and behave correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more in the report: the growth of advertising, the flow of information through social networks, apps as second screens, China (the big project there for my son to learn Chinese?), among others. Definitely worth a few minutes of reading and some time reflecting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>